Steps for Calculating a Performance Baseline
Hello, Mike Harry back again where we’re looking at baselining
and determining our opportunity error rate.
Now, let's say that per unit we have four opportunities. Again, what is an opportunity?
An opportunity is just that.
It is the chance of a defect, it's an opportunity for a defect.
And if there are four such opportunities per unit.
Again, let's go back and see what we mean by that. Back to the idea of banking.
Recall in this banking example, people are coming and going. And they come up here.
If the person calls up the wrong account. The person could fail to greet them.
This particular teller right here could fail to smile.
Fail to offer a particular service while the customer is there.
An opportunity could be anything. Now, if all of those errors, in this example,
50 such errors are made out of a thousand units and that's our unit error rate.
Given that there’s 4 opportunities, or what we might call defect categories,
then I simply take .05 divided by 4 and that's .0125
opportunities, defects per opportunity, errors per opportunity,
consequences per opportunity if you will.
Now, step number three is really simple. We take that opportunity error rate
multiply it by a million, and get 12,500 defects per million opportunities.
That's the baseline that's kind of the benchmark, if you will.
12,500 defects per million opportunities.
Now, if I know the defects per million opportunities, I can directly compare now.
The defects per million opportunities of this teller.
Of this jumper.
The defects per million delivery opportunities.
And the defects per million opportunities for deploying an airbag.
Because it's on a level playing field.
The defect rate has been reduced per million opportunities,
so that everything's on a level playing field, at this point.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.